A Guide to the Dillard family papers, 1771-1859, 189-
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Dillard family papers, 1771-1859, 189-
The Library of Virginia
53160
.37 cubic feet (1 box and 1 oversize folder)
Dillard family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased
Biographical Information
The Dillards were a prominent family in Amherst and Nelson Counties, Virginia. James Spotswood Dillard was born 29 November 1791. He married Narcissa Elizabeth Turner (1797-1878) on 17 October 1816. James Spotswood Dillard died 29 August 1866. James and Narcissa Dillard's son Terisha Washington Dillard was born 11 September 1817 and their son William S. Dillard was born about 1825. Terisha W. Dillard married Mary Elizabeth Dillard (1826-1886) 30 November 1844. Terisha Dillard was killed by enslaved persons on 9 May 1863. William S. Dillard was a physician who practiced in Nelson County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1771-1859, 189-, of the Dillard family of Amherst County, Virginia, consisting of circular letters, correspondence, letters to the editor, and speeches concerning local, state, and national politics; drawings, land grants, and plats regarding property in Amherst and Buckingham Counties; account books, accounts, and correspondence regarding purchases and financial matters; commissions for the 90th Virginia Militia; claims for property losses during the Civil War; and a business card for Dr. William S. Dillard.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1818, 1822-1823 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1843, 1849, [184-] (Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1851-1853, 1859 (Folder 3)
- Peter Martin and Company correspondence to James S. Dillard, 1855, 1857 (Folder 4)
- Stephen Turner account with Robert Rives and Company, 1798 (Folder 5)
- James S. Dillard cash account book, 1819-1821 (Folder 6)
- William S. Dillard claims, 189- (Folder 7)
- Land grants, 1789, 1821 (located in oversize folder) (Folder 8)
- Plats, 1789, 1792, no date (Folder 9)
- J. P. Dillard drawing, no date (Folder 10)
- Militia commissions, 1812, 1819, 1833 (one commission located in oversize folder) (Folder 11)
- Lord Dunmore call for elections to the House of Burgesses, 31 Ocober 1771 (Folder 12)
- Letter to the Lynchburg Republican by Eastern Virginia [Terisha W. Dillard?], 1840 (Folder 13)
- Terisha W. Dillard speech, Democratic meeting in Bedford County, Virginia, ca. 1840s (Folder 14)
- William S. Dillard business card, 1847 (Folder 15)